Guide to the Department of Sociology and Anthropology records, 1951-1955.
Department of Sociology and Anthropology records, 1951-1955
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Department of Sociology and Anthropology records, 1951-1955.
14-25-2209
Cornell University. Dept. of Sociology and Anthropology.
3 cubic ft.
Records, reports, notes, interviews, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records for a research training seminar and various other reports.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of an interdepartmental research training seminar for the social sciences including proposals; reports; faculty and student notes; project data for an Elmira voting study, 1948; and interviews from a St. Joseph's Hospital, Elmira study, 1951. Also correspondence, research reports, and internal memoranda from the Digby, Nova Scotia, Stirling County Study conducted by Alexander Leighton and Garnet E. McCreary, 1952-1955
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Leighton, Alexander.; Cornell University. Dept. of Sociology and Anthropology.
Subjects:
Anthropology--Study and teaching.; Sociology--Study and teaching.; Sociology--Methodology.; Interviewing in sociology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Series 1: Social Science Research Training Seminar
Series 2: Stirling County Study Records
CONTAINER LIST
- Interdepartment research training seminar in social sciences
  Includes training materials, outlines, interviews, evaluations; also, material related to Elmira Voting Study
  - Purpose of Course I; Skills to be Taught II (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes used in Concept of the Competent Field Worker (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Criteria for Selecting a Group (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - How We Identify Ourselves (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Professional Ethics (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Field Worker Bias - St. Paul's Hospital, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Term Papers - Outline (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appendix (Incomplete) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sociodrama - Social Growth (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Experience Gained in Teaching - Do's and Don'ts VI (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Table of Contents (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Purpose of Non-structured Interviewing and Observation (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Prelim Work on Field Research Training Program (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Term Paper by Edith M. Lentz (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Summary of Course Evaluations for W.F. Whyte (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tabulations of Student Course - Assessments (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Evaluation of Seminar (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Administration and Organization of Course III Skills to be Taught (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Interview Evaluation - Form (by Informant) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Interviewer Evaluation (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Course Assessment Sheet (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Background Information Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Student Questionnaire Forms given Fall, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Forms for Background Information on Students: Social Growth (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Final Evaluation: Field Notes, Field Interviews, Term Papers (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Rankings for Field Worker Skills (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ratings and Rankings of All Recorded Interviews (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Socio-drama, Church Board Meeting (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Techniques for Teaching Interviewing Skills (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Photographs and Interviews (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Description of Interviewing, Observations and Hypothesis (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Diplomatic Relations (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Proposed Field Projects, Fall, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Teaching Arrangements for FMTM, Fall, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Sample Interviews - E. Lentz (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Field Relations (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Field Relations (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Offprints and Articles in Field Methods (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Recording Filed Data for the File (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Leighton on Observation (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - A Pentecostal Church History (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bronfenbrenner on Unstructured Interviewing (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Natural Observation (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Fred Mitchell Case (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Outline for Observer's Report - Springdale (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Set of Notes from SAR Seminar (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Interview Records, W.W.'s Class (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Interviews with Field Workers in Experience and Skills (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Non Verbal Expression, Bobby Halpern (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - W.F. Whyte Spring Seminar in Interviewing, Steve's Notes (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Examples of Field Recording (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Meeting #1, Sept. 24, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Oct. 8, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Oct. 15, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Oct. 22, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Oct. 29, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Nov. 5, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Nov. 12, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Nov. 19, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Content and Participation Class Meeting, Dec. 10, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Materials on Interviews, Dec. 3, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Student Interviews with Veterans, Dec. 17, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Revised Proposal, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - William F. Whyte - The Meaning of Industrial Work (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Devereux - Conceptual Framework (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Final Report of Faculty Seminar (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Purpose, Student Questions - Observations (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Reports - Core Training - Documents (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Class Meeting, Jan. 7, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Sub-committee Sharp (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Progress Report: Logic (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Progress Report: Documents (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Progress Report: Content Analysis (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Progress Report: Structured (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Progress Report: Experimental (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Progress Report: Unstructured (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Subject Matter (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Method (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Training (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Evaluative Comments (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Research Training Notes (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Research Training Seminar (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Course Material for Survey of Available Courses (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - SSRC Cottrell on Research (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Seminar Surveys (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - RKG: Notes on Research Training Needs (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Research Tarining Meetings, Draft of Proposal (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Survey of Research Courses (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Research Proposal (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Agenda, Oct. 1, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Summary, Oct. 15, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Summary, Oct. 22, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Research Training Seminars, Meetings #3-15, Nov. 1951-May 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
  - Correspondence and Memos (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Wisconsin Faculty Seminar, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Report of Sub-committee, MacLeoad (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Report of Subcommittee; Williams, Lambert (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Interviews for Book on Human Relations in a Hospital - St. Joseph's (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Interviews for Book on Human Relations in a Hospital - St. Joseph's (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Interviews - Claxton Hospital, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Elmira Voting Study, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Elmira Voting Study, Interviews, John Dean (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Anaylsis of Interviews and Observation Data (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Diplomatic Relations Involved in Research (Part I) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CMT On Nat. Obs. and Interviewing Notes on Meetings (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Characteristics of the Method (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Outline, Summaries and Bibliographies (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Readings in Intern and Obs. for CORE Course (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Field Relations (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Observation (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Lab 4 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lab 3 Interviewing (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Exper. Interviews Recorded for Lab 3 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lab 3 Interviewing (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Instructions for Tests (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Syllabus for 15 Sessions (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lab Suggestions Int. and Obs. from CORE Course (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Stirling County study of community and family life in Digby, 1951-1955
  - Administrative Accounts and Bookkeeping (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence re Cornell Project (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Digby General (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Survey Publications (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Fourth Annual Report (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Early Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Research Designs - Digby GEM (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - R. Schwartz - Outgoing Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Reports - Digby, done by GEM (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Assistants - Digby Project (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Budgets - Statistical Unit (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jane Hughes - John Collier (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Clinic Financial Reports, Sept. 1954 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Job Hunting, B.D.'s Work - Spring Schedules of Social Science Unit (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Quarterly Reports (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Summary of Oct. 21, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Meetings - Psychiatric Clinic (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Notes on Latent Sturcture Analysis (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Stirling Reports (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Use of the Discriminant Function...McCreary (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Hant's-King's D.A. on Digby Evolutions (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dalton Vernon (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Digby Discriminant Rank - Ordering Males and Females Separately (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Ade Tembly - Emile Gosselin (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Frank Young D.T.A. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Yatsushiro Survey vs. Anthropology (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Land Use Planning Study (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Bruce Dohrenwend (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Poverty Class vs. Sickness Classification (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Evaluation Tabulations (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Housing Survey and Photography (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Statistics on Informants re Economic Well-being (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Plans for Evaluating Stress Factors (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Class Structure - Digby (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Digby Hosprial and Referral Cards (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Psychiatric Clinic (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Bill Longaker (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Doctor Interviewing (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Sorting of Well's and H.S. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Write-up of Stratum Impressions (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Reasons for Refusal on Survey (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Draft of Interviewer's Handbook (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Pre-test Draft of Question (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Draft I Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Draft II Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Draft III Questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - The Historical Development of Measures of Economic Well-being (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Study of Religions (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poverty - Affluence - F.L.S. Reports (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Secularization - F.L.S. Reports (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Map Index (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Criticism of Survey Method (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Technical Survey Book (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Information on Questionnaires - House Number Changes, etc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Field Notes from Summer Survey (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Survey of Family and County Life (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Statistical Supplement to the Report on "Organized Religious Life in Digby County" (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jean Cooper's Report (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Car Scale (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Lowell's Child Rearing Analysis Schedule (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 16)